topic: Vim
deck: All::CS::Tools::Vim
uid_tag: vim
notes:
        -
                uuid: 234dbb3b-bfa6-4e47-88e8-1c160d33b3af
                front: Increment/decrement current number
                back: "`C-a`, `C-x`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 3511ce47-af75-41bd-9bde-97ca608b5952
                front: Move one paragraph forward/backward
                back: "`{}`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 714f43dd-a6a7-474e-a675-f0b454b1e7bb
                front: Move one sentence forward/backward
                back: "`()`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: bbaa3261-44dd-42d1-871b-27198ba94944
                front: Go to other end of selection in visual mode
                back: "`o`"
        -
                uuid: c9a40478-0e53-44b3-82e3-2309ea4a0dc1
                front: Insert output of command
                back: "`:read !ls /home`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 33bd0e53-5c32-4324-a680-b90ab3b0143d
                front: Create mark
                back: '`mX` (`X` = mark name)'
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 3208c345-745b-4497-9145-1ab135d38dd5
                front: Go to mark
                back: "`'X` (`X` = mark name)"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 97963064-88d3-47a6-ad66-3dbe77c7c0e4
                front: Start and open a window for each file
                back: "`vim -o ...`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 6f7d2479-4ff0-4949-80bd-5b87202acde5
                front: Start and open a window for each file, split vertically
                back: "`vim -O ...`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 4f97ca60-608a-496d-aa6d-4e68d5061210
                front: Revive last selection
                back: "`gv`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 9cae9f68-eb5c-407f-9c38-e913c00d8796
                front: Run filter command over buffer
                back: "`:%!command`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 7a9b08e5-c24f-463f-ab2a-598bbb2c7aee
                front: Insert file content here
                back: |
                        `:read (file)` &mdash; aka `:r (file)`
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 52b1456c-be13-4d83-a9c5-13747a657b81
                front: Create directory for current buffer
                back: "`:!mkdir -p %:h`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 832d32a8-2b4f-4645-ad34-7f2fff5529f9
                front: Open read-only Vim
                back: "`view`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 6b6f1fe9-0716-4e56-8add-ff31ea347e8d
                front: "`M` in Normal mode"
                back: "Go to middle of page"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 810f51bb-7533-4def-bbfa-370f37538271
                front: "`H` in Normal mode"
                back: "Go to start of page"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: e04dbb9d-8b8b-40b7-9f6b-ebc9b2544e8a
                front: "`L` in Normal mode"
                back: "Go to end of page"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: ee22c0cc-cfd3-40a2-b4cd-e589a3b854eb
                front: "`]c`, `[c`"
                back: "Jump to next, previous change in `vimdiff`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: ab14f024-7f23-4a81-8f9b-fe530e9daccc
                front: "`O`"
                back: "Insert line above and start writing"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 671b3d74-9674-4a8c-ae21-628d6993b5a1
                front: "`b`"
                back: "Go back by a word"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: babee966-4538-48de-a293-a111d2746a09
                front: "`%`"
                back: "Jump to matching pair construct (`()`/`[]`/`#if`/...)"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 7b4be7c6-5975-4c21-93f1-676dd9ba62dc
                front: "`g~`"
                back: "Switch upper/lowercase in selection"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 07560444-4fff-4c82-bbe2-d7624cc45b4e
                front: "`gu`"
                back: "Switch selection to lowercase"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 23b2e89a-d396-4955-bf97-c264a5e04681
                front: "`gU`"
                back: "Switch selection to uppercase"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 358bd63c-6f53-4abf-9f0a-61a1a0b4061e
                front: "`~`"
                back: "Switch upper/lowercase of character"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: ba51a63e-4f0c-46ca-b8d3-ae654b58428d
                front: "Write buffer, appending its content to `otherfile.txt`"
                back: "`:w >>otherfile.txt`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 6fe27c8c-9748-4e13-8070-50530940c780
                front: "Jump immediately before next occurence of `x` on this line"
                back: "`tx`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 79881b2a-95a9-4266-b5ec-782a4cabd9d1
                front: "Search current word, backwards"
                back: "`#`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: c43597d2-8abf-4223-bd3e-b779977c7b06
                topic: Vim - Insert mode
                front: "Paste content of register"
                back: "`C-r (register)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 3f90fb54-db4f-4dfd-aa47-cd325b00359a
                front: "Arithmetic register"
                back: |
                        `=`
        -
                uuid: 21001fd8-5a54-4394-896e-8a90c34b155f
                topic: Vim - Insert mode
                front: "Paste 5+15"
                back: "`C-r =5+15 <Enter>`"
        -
                uuid: 808a44df-eb2d-465b-8388-1ed3e72db56f
                front: "Scroll down without changing focused line"
                back: |
                        `C-e`
                # mnemonic: "E-xtra lines"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 2cc06e7e-05a7-4dff-bfa2-b63e6c322016
                front: "Scroll up without changing focused line"
                back: |
                        `C-y`
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 2cb7bd94-3a1c-4ce6-a697-cbc0fcc56f65
                front: "Find a pattern and add something to occurences"
                back: "`:%s/pattern/&+something/` => replace `pattern` with `pattern+something`"
        -
                uuid: 006ead5b-61e6-4460-8985-6abc34894028
                front: "Open window with command history"
                back: "`q:`"
        -
                uuid: 1ea2eb93-3bba-46c5-aee9-970bd1531fb6
                topic: Vim - Insert mode
                front: "`C-w`"
                back: "Delete last word"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: e9e1434f-7db7-41de-9faf-24b8536610d6
                topic: Vim - Insert mode
                front: "`C-u`"
                back: "Backspace until start of line"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 6c1b7707-1f07-45ca-9f52-84031a5a237b
                front: "Replace current line with output of command"
                back: "`!!` (...)"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: f4d10a4a-d9a6-474b-afb7-ba15bf9e27da
                front: "Insert output of command here"
                back: "`:r!xyz`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 0f8c2e2a-f05d-424f-9d31-e0265e915286
                front: "Change window height to 35 lines"
                back: "`35 C-w _`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 8d5e9ea0-626b-4066-b175-0a0e078f8162
                front: "Change window width to 35 chars"
                back: "`35 C-w |`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: e6495158-3b99-4cba-b546-2bc1cf1be58c
                front: "Go to previous position in position stack"
                back: "`C-o`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 253a48e4-8514-41dc-8e7e-ed5f964e3fe2
                front: "Go to next position in position stack"
                back: "`C-i`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 864aed40-c3b6-4d6f-9a66-2fd8d804cf81
                front: "Change entire line"
                back: "`cc` or `C`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: ec7bbcf5-7268-4363-ac43-a390beea09cd
                front: "Get man page of current word"
                back: "`K`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 2884123c-8687-4bdd-94a1-aef170989093
                topic: Vim - Insert mode
                front: "Insert character at same position in line above"
                back: "`C-y`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: d73df7fb-a5ed-41eb-956a-15707d7ba913
                front: "Get UTF-8 representation of char"
                back: "`g8`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: ad9d0354-d668-4bfe-ab40-293f6753a109
                front: "Get ASCII representation of char, including hex"
                back: "`ga`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 00fb7dd3-0d94-4198-852c-113ff8118848
                front: "Cursor to column 10"
                back: "`10|`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 66ba953f-2a69-4e20-b168-e9b46c4fbfe2
                front: "Go to 40% of file"
                back: "`40%`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 18bb0924-c2c0-4c61-992c-945ac708dea9
                front: "Equalize windows"
                back: "`C-w =`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: d5f11805-0f18-4a3b-8713-a010ffcec95a
                front: "List errors"
                back: "`:clist`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: db2cef8d-afb6-4915-b434-748a661ae628
                front: "List errors, in new window"
                back: "`:copen`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 7599b352-1206-4916-b030-5d0dd746a6b7
                front: "List errors, including whole `makeprg` output"
                back: "`:clist!`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 1b0f12a7-5c20-4298-a2ab-e201ac97c3ff
                front: "Goto beginning of previous word"
                back: "`b`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 2ffc7d7b-4d38-4468-8aa0-2347ec47ce5d
                front: "Goto next word end"
                back: "`e`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 96faec0f-8f89-4aab-877a-b1bccaf81194
                front: "Repeat last executed macro"
                back: "`@@`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 93cfd3bf-a89d-4efe-8a7a-e974f36c6f49
                front: "Write buffer to new filename and switch to new filename"
                back: "`:saveas x`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 3c544dc9-079c-41ef-a446-fbcb83b84d09
                front: "Open file under cursor"
                back: "`gf`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 3c723e02-0c15-4f17-8f5b-93871e923092
                front: "Switch between last 2 files"
                back: "`C-^`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 2681bfd3-215f-4dce-8451-8e1a2dd7cee0
                topic: Vim - Insert mode
                front: "Do one normal mode command"
                back: "`C-o`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: d3784d82-9ae5-4181-8b08-6a7ac1ced857
                front: "Go to 100th file character"
                back: "`:goto 100`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: fd4d6e64-2aa6-4e26-a364-f4419f23e93d
                front: "Pipe buffer into the command `foo`"
                back: "`:w !foo`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 4644234c-3ca1-4ec4-9542-8cf7a1de311e
                front: "Record macro `c`"
                back: "`qc ... ... q`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: ab6f9cea-5ddb-47b5-b86b-dfcd8ac7e5e8
                front: "Play macro `c`"
                back: "`@c`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 757c252f-2222-40ff-a139-c9fd09ffb5ef
                topic: Vim - Insert mode
                front: "`C-n`"
                back: "Next autocomplete"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: c79e906a-7b09-492a-9ea7-b89db94c4053
                topic: Vim - Insert mode
                front: "`C-p`"
                back: "Previous autocomplete"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: e76217ca-e0f6-49dd-98fe-58986a5cca6a
                front: "`:cn`"
                back: "Go to next error"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: ba1f83b3-d04d-4ab1-a3d0-90584bd7c5ef
                front: "`:cc`"
                back: "Show this error's full error message"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 83bb4a81-b0bd-425e-875c-68a4b2e0eb10
                front: "`;`"
                back: "Next character search match on this line"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 41f6b66d-7dd6-4546-b66e-bc184d75abdd
                front: "`,`"
                back: "Previous character search match on this line"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 1adc19cb-5f9f-4703-802f-441eec740d28
                front: "Mark of start of last changed text (e.g., pasted)"
                back: '<code>\`[</code>'
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: db0ac34a-af2d-4e38-a8cc-d4c6bd7a5f3e
                front: "Mark of end of last changed text (e.g., pasted)"
                back: '<code>\`]</code>'
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: beb11e5a-aa12-4849-ad4a-aaa16c5bbd7f
                front: "Select last changed text (e.g., pasted)"
                back: '<code>\`[v\`]</code>'
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 9d88eca5-9bea-4fc1-bb52-032c83d1bbe8
                front: "Undo all changes on current line"
                back: "`U`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: df60586b-43da-44fd-8ecf-e6b520e19dc0
                front: "Center current line on screen"
                back: "`zz`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 20ee57ec-c2ed-4330-8b06-3192eb441e30
                front: "Rot-13 selection (Visual mode)"
                back: "`g?`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: da9b1bf4-4081-4423-a1fc-269990e3e4b9
                front: "Go to definition (globally)"
                back: "`gD`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 69418583-e1ee-4759-819c-6114d2e3be6d
                front: "Go to definition (only in current function)"
                back: "`gd`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 75f24356-4ed3-4c05-81f5-2dc8521781df
                front: "Move to next method in programming language"
                back: "`]m`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: f01825ed-f4ef-471b-b2de-c18edd3036bd
                front: "Move to previous method in programming language"
                back: "`[m`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 35d0b068-01ae-4ac9-995e-e2d8c180c3ed
                front: "Reformat current paragraph"
                back: "`{gq}`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: be75a679-f786-4a75-9f92-0f71d8b53ee4
                front: "Reformat until `(movement)`"
                back: "`gq(movement)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 71fcd542-fd41-466c-8028-0b0243ba95a4
                front: "List all marks"
                back: "`:marks`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 759c565c-acf5-43d8-9e13-789d5e5f34a5
                front: "Open and edit new buffer"
                back: "`:enew`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 9bd33989-c6b9-4f12-be08-cccd0828b282
                front: "Split vertically and explore filesystem"
                back: "`:Sex`"
                include_reverse: true
